So here's our Sudoku puzzle.
这是我们的数独问题
After running constraint propagation by iterating the functions eliminate
在执行了约束传播后 也就是不断迭代两个函数 排除法和唯一解法
and only choice we get to this point.
我们得到了这个结果
Where in each box we've recorded the values that are allowed in that box.
每个格子都写上了可以填进去的值
And let's pick one at random, say this one with values eight and nine.
我们随机挑一个 就挑这个能填 8 和 9 的吧
Since we don't know what value will go here yet,
因为我们还不知道要填什么值
we'll just consider both possibilities.
所以我们两个可能性都考虑看看
We'll try to solve a Sudoku obtained if this value's an eight.
假设值为 8 我们来试着解这个数独问题
And also the Sudoku obtained, if this value's a nine.
再假设值为 9 的情况
Thus, we start to create a tree of possibilities.
于是我们就建立了概率树
Obviously, we could have picked any other box and
显然 我们也可以挑其它格子
split it into its available values, but the reason we
并按可能值为其绘制各种情况 但之所以要挑
picked a box with only two values is because this will be less work.
只有两个可能值的格子 是因为这样工作量小些
So let's recap.
我们来复习一下
Here we have our original Sudoku and the two possibilities for
这是原始数独 格子里有两个可能值
this box, eight and nine.
8 和 9
For each of the two possibilities, we again, run constraint propagation.
我们分别对这两种可能进行约束传播
Let's say we're on one of the left.
假设我们要处理左边的这一个
After running constraint propagation, we see that we're still not done.
在进行了约束传播后 我们发现还是得不出结果
We look at one of the boxes with the fewest number of possibilities and
我们再挑一个可能值最少的格子来看
let's say it's a box here with three possibilities, one, five, and nine.
假设是这个 有三个可能值 1、5 和 9
Well now we branch out our tree again, and
再次将树分支
try to solve the three Sudoku's obtained this way.
试着解用这种办法得到的三个数独问题
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[空白音频]
Let's say we try to solve the one on the left, and
假设我们试着解了左边的这个
that one doesn't give us a solution.
仍没有得到最终解
No problem, we'll try the next one.
没事 我们试试旁边这个
Let's say this splits into two Sudoku's
假设这次分成了两个数独分支
[BLANK_AUDIO]
[空白音频]
And again, let say the one to the left doesn't reach its solution,
再一次 假设左边这个还是没有得到最终解
but the one on the right does.
但右边的这个得到了
Hooray, we're reach a solution.
太棒了 我们得到一个解了
This will be the general procedure if we don't solve the Sudoku and
这就是解数独的大致过程了 如果我们解不出数独
we get a few possibilities for some boxes will branch out and
而是得到一些格子的可能值 那我们就进行分支
try to solve the Sudoku's obtain its way.
试着解分支上的数独
If we reach a Sudoku that can't be solved then we move to the next one and
如果分支无解 那就试试另一个
we do this until we reach a solution.
循环往复 直到得到解为止
This procedure is called Depth First Search.
这个过程就叫做深度优先搜索
The Depth First Search algorithm works as follows.
深度优先搜索算法工作原理如下
We start by the root, and traverse the tree always in the leftmost fashion.
从根开始 总是从树的最左边走起
When we reach an end, we go to the next branch to the right, and keep going.
一旦走到尽头 就向右走向旁边的分支 以此类推
We'll have the chance to learn this more in detail later in the nanodegree.最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6
你可以在纳米学位课程之后的内容里进一步学习该算法.最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6